MAAZ AHMED

+92-335-3702218

maazshaikh437@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/maaz-ahmed-310484b1 () github.com/maaz437

I.T. Professional with 5+ years of professional experience in the field of System Administration, Networking, DevOps, and Desktop/Helpdesk Support. Looking for a full-time challenging position in a reputable organization, having an attractive environment, prospects of growth and learning, skills, proficiency to develop and promote creativity, and high-order thinking skills that increase performance.

EXPERIENCE

17 JUL 20223 -TO DATE

WINDOWS SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR,

BIT DEVELOPMENT (SANDLINE GLOBAL), KARACHI

- Administered both local and remote servers and network operations
- Managed over 80+ virtual machines (VMs) across multiple data centers
- Administrated and monitored Windows Servers as well as Ubuntu and CentOS Linux servers
- Handled administrative tasks such as configuring, patching, upgrading, backup, and troubleshooting
- Managed and configured FortiGate Firewalls for network security.
- Handled Cisco switches and wireless controllers to maintain network connectivity and performance.
- Managed user accounts and access using Microsoft Office 365 (O365).
- Implemented compliance policies for end users to ensure security and regulatory compliance.
- Administered and monitored infrastructure and system logs, including firewalls and endpoint security systems.
- Ensured the implementation of security measures to protect the network and systems from potential threats.
- Provided helpdesk assistance to resolve software, hardware, and network-related problems for end users.

16 JUN 2022 - 14 JUL 2023

DESKTOP SUPPORT GLOBAL IT & OPS (OG-II),

HBZ SERVICES (HABIB BANK AG ZURICH), KARACHI

- Assist Sr. System Administrator in building and maintaining Server administration, and operating systems.
- Log and resolve Laptop/Desktop, Network/ISP, and NOC incidents through ITSM
- Implementation of Compliance policies at End users.
- Working on different projects e.g., Bit-Locker implementation, Kubernetes Cluster deployment in a Hybrid Environment, VM Patching, and Network Migration.
- Vendor coordination for Laptop/Desktop, Network/ISP and peripheral maintenance
- Resolve IT services issues/requests by following the SOPs

- Escalate IT services issues by following the escalation matrix
- Work with hiring managers to order hardware/software for new employees and set up new workstations promptly

26 APR 2021 - 15 JUN 2022

INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER (BPS-15),

DIAGNOSTIC & RESEARCH LABORATORY (LUMHS), KARACHI

- Administered all network operations both local and remote
- Administer 40+ VMs environment with 100% uptime
- Configured and installed FortiGate Firewalls, Cisco switches, and wireless controllers
- Provide helpdesk assistance in resolving software, hardware, and network-related problems
- Administrating and monitoring Windows Servers, Ubuntu /Centos Linux servers
- Administrating, configuring, patching, upgrading, backup, and troubleshooting physical and virtual servers (rack mounts, and VMs)
- Administrating and monitoring Endpoint Point Protection Server (Kaspersky)
- Administer & monitor infrastructure and system logs, including firewalls, Endpoint Protection, and other processes

17 JUL 2017 - 31 MAY 2021

DATABASE/SYSTEM ADMIN (BPS-11),

COMBINED MILITARY HOSPITAL, HYDERABAD

- Administrating, configuring, patching, upgrading, and troubleshooting physical and virtual servers (rack mounts and VMs)
- IT operations processes e.g., patch management, Active Directory user management, HMS Application user management etc.
- Administrating and monitoring Red Hat/ Ubuntu /Centos Linux servers
- Maintained operations of existing network infrastructure and troubleshoot problems timely
- Master Trainer of Hospital Management System Application
- Administrate & monitor infrastructure and system logs, including firewalls, databases, malware protection software, and other processes
- Provide support to all users and keep a track record
- Maintaining the integrity of the network, server deployment, and system security
- Assist seniors in ensuring security and efficiency through access controls

02 FEB 2016 - 30 JUN 2017

NETWORKS ENGINEER INTERN,

FUTURE SOLUTION PROVIDER, HYDERABAD

- Assist Network Administrator in building and maintaining computer networks, server applications, and operating systems
- Configured and installed router switches and wireless controllers
- Provide helpdesk assistance in resolving software, hardware, and network-related problems
- Perform troubleshooting, archiving, and backup of server applications

EDUCATION

JULY 2020

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION SECURITY,

NED UET KARACHI

MARCH 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY,

SINDH AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- CISCO CERTIFICATIONS
 (CCNA ROUTING AND SWITCHING) (CCNA SECURITY)
- AWS CERTIFICATION (AWS Solution Architect)
- FORTIGATE CERTIFICATION (NSE1) (NSE2)
- MICROSOFT CERTIFICATIONS
 (MOS) (MICROSOFT CERTIFIED SOLUTIONS ASSOCIATE OFFICE 365) (AZURE ADMINISTRATOR)
- HUAWEI CERTIFICATION (HCIA ROUTING & SWITCHING)

SKILLS

- Virtualization
- Networking
- Windows Server
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Jenkins
- GIT / GitHub
- Ansible

- Terraform
- IT Security
- Veeam backup
- Linux Server
- Active Directory
- VMware ESXI
- MRTG
- VPN

- DNS
- DHCP
- Kaspersky
- Hyper-V
- NFS
- Office 365
- CCTV
- GPO

REFERENCE

Available on Request